Rajan Sharma

Nawalpur, Nepal

🔀 raaznn.sharma@gmail.com
+977 9817294181, +977 9845817163

About me

I'm a frontend developer with over 3 years of experience in web development. I develop new user-facing features using React.js, translate designs and wireframes into high-quality code, build reusable components and front-end libraries for future use and optimize components for maximum performance across a vast array of web-capable devices and browsers

Skills

- HTML5, CSS3 & JavaScript ES6+
- SCSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap & Material UI
- React with Hooks & Redux

- Data Visualization with D3.js
- Testing with Jest
- Webpack & Firebase

Employment

Frontend Developer

AStrick IT Company 2019 - 2020

- · Built frontend of web applications using using html, css, javascript & bootstrap
- · Closely worked with back-end developers to optimize existing Web technology and create the best possible user experience.

Frontend Developer (React)

Intelzy Software Company · 2020 - 2022

- · Developed responsive web applications with React.js
- \cdot Collaborated with the design team to create UI/UX for the applications.
- · optimize frontend components for maximum performance.

Experience

DeFi News (demo)

Decentralized Finance News Articles Web App that uses Zebec Protocol under solana blockchain for payment stream when users read the articles. It was mentioned as Honorable Mentions in <u>Zebec Protocol's global hackathon 2021</u>

ML-Solution (demo)

A web based GUI application for generating Machine Learning Models by uploading dataset as an csv file and selecting the attributes for the model. It provides visualization of datasets in various formats and allows users to download the generated model in different file types (example: pickle file).

Education

Bachelor's in Computer Science & Information Technology
<u>Lumbini ICT Campus</u> (Tribhuvan University affiliated), Nawalpur, Nepal 2015 to 2019

Certifications

- Responsive Web Design
- JavaScript Algorithms & Data Structures
- Front End Development Libraries

- Data Visualization
- MongoDB Basic